in this episode we're going to take a step back
back to one of the most important tasks when you
work as a GrandMA3 programmer this granuma3
tutorial is all about the merge override and
remove function you use when you start to make
some actual programming understanding those
functions is something you must master if you
want to work as a GrandMA3 programmer storing
something into a sequence is easy and something
everybody can do but removing values from your
GrandMA3 sequences and cues is equally
important and it's something you have to know
to be a fast and good GrandMA3 programmer
so without further ado let's just get into it
first let's look at the GrandMA3 merge
function the merge function will prompt you if
you are trying to store something into an already
existing queue as you can see i prepared a little
scene for us here with a lot of this time mega
points let's just select all of them like this
and turn them on at full and maybe put them
into a position so this is basically just a
normal you put in some lights in a position and
you turn them on you want to store it somewhere
so let's just store this into our sequence right
here and as you can see it created cue number one
if we uh clear this scene and we go this cue list
you can see we now have all our mega points let's
do the same for our two lights and put some two
lights on at full like this you can see there
up right now once again we can simply store
this into the same sequence and it's going
to ask us what do you want to do in this case i
want to merge it into the same cue as i'm in
already so if i just press merge and i clear
my console you can see everything is now
into our master sequence and this is basically
the most simple function ever this is merge you
can put something on top of other things into
your sequence and that is very very easy to do
you will find yourself merging into cues all the
time as a GrandMA3 programmer now we master
the merge function and in a minute we'll take a
look at the GrandMA3 override function but just
before we do that if you like this content and
get any value out of this video be sure to give
it a like liking the videos is a free and good
way to support any youtube channel with that
out of the way let's just continue let's take a
look at option number two when you store into an
existing cue on a GrandMA3 console this time
we're going to talk about the override function
so the override function takes something
and replaces it with something else that's
basically what's happening here so let's
just take all our two lights here and
just turn them off and store that into our
sequence right here and let's just merge it
in for now we clear it out and you as you
can see all the two lights are gone again
now we have all our mega points on and all our
two lights off let's say we turn all our two
lights on again and we say store into cue number
one and we say override as you can see all the
mega points disappeared and all the two lights are
left we clear out here and you you can simply see
everything we put into our programmer we
stored that into the cue and we removed
everything else that was already in the cue
that is basically how the override function works
the override function works if you take something
into your programmer and you say okay this is my
new cue this is i know my my cue was like this
before but now this is the way i want it you can
simply store it into your cue and say override
it replaces everything with the new look you just
made next up is the remove function but before
that i'll urge you to leave a comment below if
you have any questions or comments to this video
i love to help you if you get stuck with something
in these GrandMA3 tutorial videos and check out
the links below if you want to look at some real
GrandMA3 hardware it'll tell you what you need to
know in terms of what the different models have to
offer but last but not least let's look at the
remove option removing values from your cues
is just as important as merging them into your
cues in the first place knowing how the GrandMA3
console removes values from your cues will
help you later down the line when you must change
something in your existing programming and it will
help you when you start learning about tracking on
the GrandMA3 console we'll not get into tracking
in this tutorial but we definitely will in one of
the next episodes just remember that tracking
is really important removing values is really
important and as you can see here we just simply
just continue with all our two lights they are all
turned on if we want to remove some of them out
of our programming we could simply just start by
taking them like this and we could turn them
off but if we turn them off we still have
a heart value recorded into our cue and this
is not what we need we want to remove the value
completely so right now they are turned off
and that means the dimmer is active and we
can now remove the active parameter and since the
demo is active right now we can simply say store
into the cue we just made and we can say remove
and when we clear this you can see they're gone
and they're completely gone from this one all
out all the values are completely gone in the
in the sequence sheet or sorry the fixture sheet
up here so this is basically how you remove values
and as i said tracking is really important and
in one of the next episodes we're going to look
at tracking because this is something you really
have to know how to remove values and add values
and make sure that it tracks uh in the
right order but that's for a another video
i hope this video gives you a better
understanding of what you need to do
when you are working with creating your
GrandMA3 show you have to know to
get values into your sequences but it's equally
important to be able to remove values as well
if you want to know more about working with
the the GrandMA3 console check out this
next video linked on the screen right now where
i will show you even more tips and tricks you
need as a GrandMA3 programmer but until i see
you the next time happy GrandMA3 programming